<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex and Nina's Travels</title>
    <atom:link href="https://alexninatravel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io</link>
    <description>Our adventures around the world.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 11 - Faro</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-11/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last day in Portugal… After packing everything, we made our way to Faro.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; We got lunch there and had a walk around the town, while buying some last-minute souvenirs and treats. We also went to Decathlon in XXX (shopping centre) to get some diving gloves, then returned the car at the airport and flew back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the journey back we watched The Martian, not as awesome as the book but still pretty good! The movie was too long for the flight so we finished it on the Gatwick express back to Victoria. And by the way we had about 2 minutes between the moment we collected our suitcases in London and the train departure so we had to run for our lives - closing the loop. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 10 - Lagos</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-10/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More beach! After trying a couple, we finally found one that was relatively shielded from the waves.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This time I joined for snorkeling and between the waves and the cold, I thought I was going to die. We made it to this rock [photo] and back, and I quickly jumped out of my wetsuit and laid on the beach for the rest of the day instead, while Alex went back.
Not much more to say, except that I downloaded a game called Atomas that day and played the whole afternoon like an addict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At dinner time we went back to the same restaurant and once more, got excellent food and service. And once more, we were too busy enjoying to take pictures (sorry!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 9 - Sagres</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-9/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a huge breakfast (included with the room), we set off to the beach. The weather was really nice again, and I couldn’t wait to go swim.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Our first stop 2 hours away was at Sagres, very famous for surfing. The sea was quite wavy and we contemplated renting surf boards but decided to keep driving and find a nice place to go snorkeling. Back in the suffocatingly hot car for a little while, and we got to XXX. After a short hike down some stairs, we got an amazing view, but still no swimmable beach. I went from happy and excited to annoyed real quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the next location was perfect for swimming. We quickly got into our wetsuits and dived into the water. Even through the wetsuit, I was feeling really cold and my hands were freezing. Still, just being in the ocean was supremely cool. Alex went snorkeling a bit further away and I just stayed on the beach, trying to warm up under the 4pm sun and drying my clothes BBQ style on the stair handle (wetsuit, obviously, but my trousers and shoes were also drenched from walking on the beach and getting caught by a wave).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a nice shower at the guesthouse, we went for dinner at XXX. It was a small restaurant on the seaside, owned and run by a jovial Londoner. The dog, Alfie, was one of the nicest people I’ve ever met. And his food was delicious.
[photos]
No photo of the main dish because it looked and smelled so tasty we couldn’t wait to dig into it. It was a mix of beef steak, pork ribs and chicken breast on the grill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if one dessert wasn’t enough, Alex insisted on going for ice cream on our way back to the hotel, which promptly fell to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 8 - Evora</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-8/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Breakfast that morning was a unique experience: eating with one hand while using the other one to fend off all the hungry pets simultaneously coming for our food. We mostly managed to keep them away, though we did lose a piece of cheese and bread to a skillful cat while we were busy clearing up the table. &lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a hard time leaving the house, it was such a lovely place with fun companions. Eventually we went for a quick tour of Evora’s Roman ruins and church [more history], and had a look around the artisans’ shops on XXX street. On the same street, we went for lunch in Momentos. The menu sounded quite attractive, but the waiter completely won Alex over when he said “we serve our dishes with locally-sourced, organic vegetables – not the usual pasta, fries or rice”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to go to the beach! We drove down along the coast towards XXX. We had been lucky with the weather that far, but on the first day that we went to the beach, it was cold and rainy. It was still a nice experience, we got an amazing view of the waves from a secluded beach near XXX. When it was time to leave, our wheels got stuck in the sand and we couldn’t start the car. Thankfully, a group of young locals happened to be in the area and helped us push the car.
We drove down a bit further and Alex decided to go for a swim (again, without his wetsuit) and I waited and waited with my camera ready for XXX minutes to catch the moment when he would finally go in. He didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Villa Nova de Milfontes that night. The hosts had an internal courtyard with a main building, and 3 other guest apartments. We were in one of them, which had 2 bedrooms, a kitchen / living-room area, bathroom, and even a washing machine.
I was already in bed and half asleep when Alex told me the kitchen smelled like gas so he turned the heater off and opened the door to bring some air in. (not sure if it’s worth telling. If so, elaborate more)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 7 - Lisbon, Nossa Senhora de Machede</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-7/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to spend 2 full days in Lisbon but unfortunately our next airbnb host needed us to arrive early, so we only had time for a couple more touristy stuff in the morning.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Photos]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While having lunch, we realised we underestimated the time it would take to get to our next location. Once again, we had to leave precipitously and rush.
Alex was speeding like a madman on the motorway, until I noticed our tank was almost empty. The next gas station being a whole 30km away, we had to stick to 50km/h to use as little fuel as possible – not only was all the time we saved by speeding lost, but we really thought we would end up stranded on the motorway, not make it in time, and have nowhere to sleep. Fortunately, we barely just made it in time to the gas station. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met the host near Nossa Senhora de Machede’s church, and she led us through dirt roads to her house in the countryside.There we were greeted by her 4 dogs and even more cats. One of the dogs, Benny, was a jumpy teenager always eager to play and get cuddles. Every time another pet got some attention, he would barge in and steal it back. Good thing teenage dogs don’t have access to facebook or instagram. The house had an immense backyard and was surrounded by wild grass and bushes, perfect for a little walk with the pets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nossa Senhora de Machede is such a small village that it only has 3 restaurant/bar/pubs, all next to each other. We picked one at random to try some very famous Black Porc (Iberian Porc), a local specialty. [more info on this]. And it did not disappoint, the whole meal was just delicious. People in general are very friendly in Portugal, but the owner of the restaurant just seemed extraordinarily nice and caring. At the end of the meal we were prepared to tip loads but instead he made us pay even less, despite our protestations, so I left feeling all guilty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in the countryside means no light pollution, which means I got to see stars for the first time in months, possibly years. On our way back to the house, we stopped the car and did some star gazing, it was wonderful. The only negative point was, and I can’t believe I’m about to say this, that the full moon was too bright and hiding most of the stars. #thirdworldproblem&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 6 - Lisbon</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-6/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the parking spot we found the previous day was only free until 9am so Alex had to go find another spot.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
In the meantime, I decided to cook breakfast with leftovers from previous days (and the ton of spinach we bought at the fruit market). The kitchen was well equipped and had all my favourite ingredients: olive oil, provence herbs, nutmeg. I went craaazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We basically spend the whole day doing standard touristy things in Lisbon: Rossio place, Commerce square (??), riverside, Alfama (the oldest part of the city). In Alfama we stopped for coffee in a cozy little place, and ended up staying for one and a half hours (they had fast wifi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way back, we went back to the market on XXX to buy biscuits, jams and charcuterie, and some food for dinner. That night was the only single time we stayed home and cooked for dinner. For dessert we got 2 traditional pastries: the rock and the torch. The rock wasn’t nearly as good as I was hoping, but the torch was blatantly disgusting – it was basically 100% sugar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 5 - Sintra</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-5/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alarm rang at 7:30.
Went back to sleep.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Alex got up to get coffee, came back after what felt like 30 seconds (but was really 20 minutes) to drag me out of bed military-style.
Got ready in 5 minutes, grabbed a snack, and off to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the member of staff we spoke to the previous day gave us wrong prices for the day pass, and the actual price was supposed to be higher. We got away with paying the lower price, but I hope we didn’t get her into trouble.
For some reason they had French TV in the gym so I did squats to the sweet sound of Diam’s music – let’s keep this a one-time thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a well deserved breakfast and shower, we drove up to Sintra to visit the Pena National Palace. [history/description]
I was having a hard time reconciling the XXX of its construction (?) and historical importance, with the fact that it looks just like a fake plastic-y castle from Disneyworld built in the 90s. Seriously, I was singing It’s a Small World the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the visit, we also walked around the gigantic park around the castle, and that was some serious exercise. Not only is everything far from everything else, but the whole estate is built on freaking hills. After we climbed up the highest viewpoint of the park, we could see the castle literally on another hill more than 1km away. Who thought it would be a good idea to design and deliver this castle to a member of nobility, and be like “there you go, now you can be trapped in your castle forever because let’s be honest, you will never be bothered to walk past the frontsteps”? Needless to say, that was the most hardcore leg day in my entire life.
Despite all the efforts, the visit was actually amazing. The park being so huge, we were often away from other tourists and able to enjoy quiet, nature, and the magnificent view of the Sintra-Cascais Natural Park around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there was one place that we were expecting to be flat, it sure was Lisbon. Well nope, just as hill-y as the rest of Portugal.
Our first endeavour was to find food though, and one of the recommended places was XXX. They’re a tiny place with 2 employees and nowhere to sit, and it smells heavenly. We got a grilled meat mix to takeaway and ate in the car like savages – sloppy, but so damn good.
As usual, we struggled to find a parking spot but finally made it to the airbnb flat. We vaguely thought about going out and experience the Lisbon nightlife, but laziness got the best of us and we opted for an early night instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 4 - Caldas de Rainha, Peniche</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-4/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of Caldas de Rainha’s famous attractions is the fruit market, the only market to be open daily in all of Portugal.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The market even gives its name to the square where it’s held, Praca de Fruta, and is well known to have high quality fresh products. In about 20 minutes of going around it, we bought almost 2kg of fruits and vegetables, which lasted us until the end of the trip (and we even brought some apples back).
That day we had lunch in the best ranked restaurant in the town: XX. Not only was the food excellent, but the service was very friendly (and they had wifi!). Alex was talking about getting a haircut that same day, and very conveniently we found a hairdresser / tattoo artist right next to the restaurant. Unfortunately they were just closing as we came in. Side note: the trending hairstyle in Portugal is shaved/short sides with a gelled puff on top (i.e. what I call “the footballer’s haircut”) – we saw variations placarde across every single hairdresser’s window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next destination: Peniche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peniche intro
We went to visit the famous Fort, but not before having a nap on the rocks nearby (because priorities). Info/description on the Fort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we still had a couple of hours before checking in, we had a walk on the cliffs at Cabo Carvoeiro.
{Picture of Nau dos Corvos}
{Picture of the circle of life}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we had a gigantic “seafood platter for 2” that could have easily fed 4 people. Needless to say we couldn’t finish it, although we did eat most of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night was the worst night ever because everything smelled damp and the bed was squeaky. Or, maybe it was because on the way home from dinner we drove past a gym, drove back there, parked the car, inquired about opening times and prices, and beaming Alex said “nice, we can wake up at 7 tomorrow and go train you”. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 3 - Serra da Estrela, Coimbra</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-3/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As soon as the alarm went off, I kicked Alex out of bed. The plan was for him to go back to the restaurant to get breakfast, while I showered and got ready &lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;– I decided to skip breakfast, not wanting to get car sick during the mountain drive. I sleepily stepped into the shower and, surprise surprise, realised I’d bought hair conditioner instead of shampoo (classic me). “Meh, that will do for the rest of the trip I guess”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were finally ready to go, we followed the GPS for about 7km to the Poço do Inferno waterfall. It was quite impressive but the name, literally meaning “Pit of Hell”, set significantly higher expectations. After a short walk on the wooden stairs and walkway, we got to the foot of the waterfall. The water was crystal clear, but freezing. Alex decided to go for a swim in his trunks (“erm, you know you have a wetsuit in the car right? That you bought especially for this trip?”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex to tell about his swimming (near death) experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way to the next destination, we drove up the mountain to 1700m of altitude. At some point it got so foggy that we could barely see a few meters in front of us, and cars seemed to be emerging from nowhere.
We got to the XXX dam, hoping to see Covao dos Conchos [more description]. We walked around the dam for a bit, and hike a little further back. When it started hailing, we made our way back to the shop near the parking lot. The owner was selling all sorts of artisanal products: cheese, sausage, gloves, hats, furs, souvenirs. We bought some sausage and a pair of gloves for Alex, while playing with 2 little puppies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To our disappointment, the shop owner told us that Covao dos Conchos was a 2 hours hike away, and that it would be night by the time we made it back. No thanks. 
Instead, we stuck to the plan and went to visit Coimbra. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coimbra was the political centre of Portugal for a long period, and was actually the Kingdom of Portugal’s capital from 1131 to 1255, before transitioning to a major cultural centre. The University, established in 1290, is the oldest academic institution in the Portuguese-speaking world. 
We parked next to the cathedral and were planning to visit it, but the entrance was paid so we lol-nope’ed around and left. We walked through the old centre, down to the pedestrian street rua Ferreira Borges. There we found a bakery, or pastelaria, with yummy-looking treats, and got a few to try. In the time it took for us to order and pay, it had started raining pretty violently so we decided to eat inside and have some tea as well. We left when it got a bit better but we still got wet on our way to the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next airbnb reservation was in Caldas da Rainha, and it was a freaking palace. Large kitchen, even larger living room, tiled walls, wooden staircase and floor, 3 guest bedrooms…and the guest bathroom {photo + caption “yes I had a bath”}. 
We went for dinner at a place recommended by the hosts, Maratona. They served massive burgers and fries for about €6/pp. We also ordered freshly pressed fruit juice and had a strawberry-parmesan cake for dessert. Me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 2 - Viseu, Manteigas</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-2/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our first breakfast in Portugal, our decision-making process was the following: go to the nearest place that serves coffee and eat whatever they have. Boom, sorted.
After a short drive, we arrived in Viseu to see more azulejos around the main square..
{Photo of the azulejo. Caption; failed panoramic photo}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also stopped at Spar to get some food supplies, and because I forgot to pack shampoo. We ended up getting 5L of water (that we carried around until the very last day of the trip and didn’t finish) and loads of biscuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next destination was Manteigas, a small village in the Serra da Estrela Natural Park. We were a bit confused about where to go, since the airbnb website and google maps gave us 2 different locations. We decided to go with airbnb’s and drove around the natural park to get to a tiny village named near Covilha. All of the inhabitants were shooting us funny looks, as if we were the first visitors in months - which was most probably the case. We found the address and parked in front of the house and waited for the host to arrive. Of course, it was the wrong place. O Google, prithee forgive us f’r doubting thee. More emergency-driving to the actual place 20 minutes away, because guess what, the host had to leave for work soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Screenshot of where we were and where we were supposed to be]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house was located on the mountainside and offered a magnificent of the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a nice dinner at Restaurante Santa Luzia, we went to bed early in preparation for some hiking the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portugal: Day 1 - Flight to Porto</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/portugal-day-1/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first day of our Portugal trip was hectic to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an intense week of rehearsals and 3 consecutive KCL dance show performances, we woke up at 7 on Saturday morning. Brutal.
Crisis number one: Alex wasn’t done packing so he spent over an hour frantically running around the house with his packing list in hand. Eventually we set off and after a speedy drive to Victoria station and a sprint to the platform, we made it on the train to Gatwick…phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flight was uneventful from my perspective - I snoozed the whole time. At Porto airport we took a shuttle to the car rental area and picked up our Volkswagen Up (if they only knew what was going to happen to it…). Finally, the real trip was about to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porto is the second largest city in Portugal and one of the oldest European centres with the earliest settlements dating back to 300 BC - in fact, its Celtic-Latin name, Portus Cales, is the origin of the country’s name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in the centre, we experienced for the first time the joys of looking for a parking spot in Portugal. After going in circles for about 20 minutes, we finally parked on a dodgy hill next to the station (not sure we were even allowed to park there!).
We started our exploration of the historic centre with the São Bento train station, famous for its azulejo panels. Designed by Jorge Colaço, the most important azulejo painter of his time, and constituted of 20,000 tiles, they depict landscapes, ethnographic scenes and historical events.
After having a quick look at the Porto cathedral, we headed off to the Sao Francisco Church, considered to be one of Brazil’s most magnificent churches. Unfortunately, it was closed so we couldn’t see the inside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disappointment didn’t last long as it was time for an equally (who am I kidding, it was actually an even more) exciting activity: dinner. We picked a restaurant next to the station suggested by tripadvisor, Tapabento, but without a reservation it was impossible to get a table. The lady recommended us another place nearby called Cantina 32, and even phoned them to make sure we would get a table. The food and service were great – we had grilled prawns with fries, salad and couscous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halfway through dinner, our airbnb host sent us a message saying that she had to leave soon and we needed to get the keys from her. We originally agreed to meet her at 18:30 but thought she would be home the rest of the evening - apparently not, she was off to the North of Portugal for the weekend. We shoved as much food as we could down our throats, paid for the meal, ran to the car, and emergency-drove to her place in 20 minutes. That was crisis number 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After settling in our room, we realised we didn’t have any drinking water. “No problemo” we thought, “there is a Froiz in the centre that closes in 15 minutes”. We made it, got water, all was good. That was until the GPS ran out of battery and the charging cable refused to work - crisis number 3. We tried to find our way back but of course got lost instead, drove up and down what felt like every single goddamn hill in that stupid town, and finally got home an hour later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/hello-world/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your new blog! This is the default blog template with RSS, pagination and an archive. There are other templates available – run &lt;code&gt;wintersmith new --help&lt;/code&gt; to list them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_repeat-after-me-_-this-is-my-blog-there-are-many-like-it-but-this-one-is-mine-my-blog-is-my-best-friend-it-is-my-life-i-must-master-it-as-i-must-master-my-life-my-blog-without-me-is-useless-without-my-blog-i-am-useless-&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Repeat after me:&lt;/em&gt; This is my blog. There are many like it, but this one is mine. My blog is my best friend. It is my life. I must master it as I must master my life. My blog, without me, is useless. Without my blog, I am useless.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, now, the directory structure of your blog is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;├── config.json               &amp;lt;- site configuration
├── contents
│   ├── about.md
│   ├── archive.json
│   ├── articles              &amp;lt;– each article has its own directory
│   │   ├── another-test
│   │   │   └── index.md
│   │   ├── bamboo-cutter
│   │   │   ├── index.md
│   │   │   └── taketori_monogatari.jpg
│   │   ├── hello-world
│   │   │   └── index.md
│   │   ├── markdown-syntax
│   │   │   └── index.md
│   │   └── red-herring
│   │       ├── banana.png
│   │       └── index.md
│   ├── authors               &amp;lt;- author metadata, check author.jade
│   │   ├── baker.json
│   │   └── the-wintersmith.json
│   ├── css
│   │   └── main.css
│   └── feed.json
├── plugins
│   └── paginator.coffee      &amp;lt;- paginator plugin
├── templates
│   ├── archive.jade
│   ├── article.jade
│   ├── author.jade
│   ├── feed.jade
│   ├── index.jade
│   └── layout.jade
└── views
    └── articles.coffee       &amp;lt;- view that lists articles
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Articles are sorted by date and 3 are shown per page, you can configure this and more in config.json. Check paginator.coffee for all options related to pagination, most plugins also have their own options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-typical-article&quot;&gt;A typical article&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-markdown&quot;&gt;---
title: Hear me blog
author: johndoe
&lt;span class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;date: 2012-12-12 12:12
---&lt;/span&gt;

This will be shown as the article excerpt.

&lt;span class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;## A h2, hr or &amp;lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&amp;gt; marks where the intro cuts off&lt;/span&gt;

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod
tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam,
quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo
consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse
cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non
proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;links-in-the-markdown-to-other-items-in-the-content-tree-will-be-resolved-for-you-&quot;&gt;Links in the markdown to other items in the content tree will be resolved for you.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example a link to &lt;code&gt;../bamboo-cutter/index.md&lt;/code&gt; resolves to &lt;a href=&quot;https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/bamboo-cutter/index.md&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/articles/bamboo-cutter/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I leave you to your own devices. Join &lt;strong&gt;#wintersmith&lt;/strong&gt; on freenode if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown syntax</title>
      <link>https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/markdown-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alexninatravel.github.io/articles/markdown-syntax/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Full markdown syntax taken from John Gruber’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt;.
Did you know that 9 out of 10 bloggers prefer to write in markdown?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;markdown-syntax&quot;&gt;Markdown: Syntax&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#philosophy&quot;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#html&quot;&gt;Inline HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#autoescape&quot;&gt;Automatic Escaping for Special Characters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#block&quot;&gt;Block Elements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#p&quot;&gt;Paragraphs and Line Breaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#header&quot;&gt;Headers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#blockquote&quot;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#list&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#precode&quot;&gt;Code Blocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hr&quot;&gt;Horizontal Rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#span&quot;&gt;Span Elements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#link&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#em&quot;&gt;Emphasis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#img&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#misc&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#backslash&quot;&gt;Backslash Escapes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#autolink&quot;&gt;Automatic Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This document is itself written using Markdown; you
can &lt;a href=&quot;https://alexninatravel.github.io/projects/markdown/syntax.text&quot;&gt;see the source for it by adding ‘.text’ to the URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;philosophy&quot;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown is intended to be as easy-to-read and easy-to-write as is feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readability, however, is emphasized above all else. A Markdown-formatted
document should be publishable as-is, as plain text, without looking
like it’s been marked up with tags or formatting instructions. While
Markdown’s syntax has been influenced by several existing text-to-HTML
filters – including &lt;a href=&quot;http://docutils.sourceforge.net/mirror/setext.html&quot;&gt;Setext&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aaronsw.com/2002/atx/&quot;&gt;atx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://textism.com/tools/textile/&quot;&gt;Textile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://docutils.sourceforge.net/rst.html&quot;&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.triptico.com/software/grutatxt.html&quot;&gt;Grutatext&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ettext.taint.org/doc/&quot;&gt;EtText&lt;/a&gt; – the single biggest source of
inspiration for Markdown’s syntax is the format of plain text email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, Markdown’s syntax is comprised entirely of punctuation
characters, which punctuation characters have been carefully chosen so
as to look like what they mean. E.g., asterisks around a word actually
look like *emphasis*. Markdown lists look like, well, lists. Even
blockquotes look like quoted passages of text, assuming you’ve ever
used email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;Inline HTML&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown’s syntax is intended for one purpose: to be used as a
format for &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is not a replacement for HTML, or even close to it. Its
syntax is very small, corresponding only to a very small subset of
HTML tags. The idea is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to create a syntax that makes it easier
to insert HTML tags. In my opinion, HTML tags are already easy to
insert. The idea for Markdown is to make it easy to read, write, and
edit prose. HTML is a &lt;em&gt;publishing&lt;/em&gt; format; Markdown is a &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt;
format. Thus, Markdown’s formatting syntax only addresses issues that
can be conveyed in plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any markup that is not covered by Markdown’s syntax, you simply
use HTML itself. There’s no need to preface it or delimit it to
indicate that you’re switching from Markdown to HTML; you just use
the tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only restrictions are that block-level HTML elements – e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;table&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, etc. – must be separated from surrounding
content by blank lines, and the start and end tags of the block should
not be indented with tabs or spaces. Markdown is smart enough not
to add extra (unwanted) &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags around HTML block-level tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to add an HTML table to a Markdown article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is a regular paragraph.

&amp;lt;table&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;Foo&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;

This is another regular paragraph.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that Markdown formatting syntax is not processed within block-level
HTML tags. E.g., you can’t use Markdown-style &lt;code&gt;*emphasis*&lt;/code&gt; inside an
HTML block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Span-level HTML tags – e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;del&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; – can be
used anywhere in a Markdown paragraph, list item, or header. If you
want, you can even use HTML tags instead of Markdown formatting; e.g. if
you’d prefer to use HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags instead of Markdown’s
link or image syntax, go right ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike block-level HTML tags, Markdown syntax &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; processed within
span-level tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;autoescape&quot;&gt;Automatic Escaping for Special Characters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In HTML, there are two characters that demand special treatment: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt;
and &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;. Left angle brackets are used to start tags; ampersands are
used to denote HTML entities. If you want to use them as literal
characters, you must escape them as entities, e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ampersands in particular are bedeviling for web writers. If you want to
write about ‘AT&amp;amp;T’, you need to write ‘&lt;code&gt;AT&amp;amp;amp;T&lt;/code&gt;‘. You even need to
escape ampersands within URLs. Thus, if you want to link to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://images.google.com/images?num=30&amp;amp;q=larry+bird
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;you need to encode the URL as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://images.google.com/images?num=30&amp;amp;amp;q=larry+bird
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;in your anchor tag &lt;code&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; attribute. Needless to say, this is easy to
forget, and is probably the single most common source of HTML validation
errors in otherwise well-marked-up web sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown allows you to use these characters naturally, taking care of
all the necessary escaping for you. If you use an ampersand as part of
an HTML entity, it remains unchanged; otherwise it will be translated
into &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you want to include a copyright symbol in your article, you can write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;copy;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;and Markdown will leave it alone. But if you write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;AT&amp;amp;T
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown will translate it to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;AT&amp;amp;amp;T
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, because Markdown supports &lt;a href=&quot;#html&quot;&gt;inline HTML&lt;/a&gt;, if you use
angle brackets as delimiters for HTML tags, Markdown will treat them as
such. But if you write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;4 &amp;lt; 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown will translate it to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;4 &amp;amp;lt; 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, inside Markdown code spans and blocks, angle brackets and
ampersands are &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; encoded automatically. This makes it easy to use
Markdown to write about HTML code. (As opposed to raw HTML, which is a
terrible format for writing about HTML syntax, because every single &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt;
and &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; in your example code needs to be escaped.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;block&quot;&gt;Block Elements&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&quot;p&quot;&gt;Paragraphs and Line Breaks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paragraph is simply one or more consecutive lines of text, separated
by one or more blank lines. (A blank line is any line that looks like a
blank line – a line containing nothing but spaces or tabs is considered
blank.) Normal paragraphs should not be indented with spaces or tabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implication of the “one or more consecutive lines of text” rule is
that Markdown supports “hard-wrapped” text paragraphs. This differs
significantly from most other text-to-HTML formatters (including Movable
Type’s “Convert Line Breaks” option) which translate every line break
character in a paragraph into a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to insert a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; break tag using Markdown, you
end a line with two or more spaces, then type return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, this takes a tad more effort to create a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, but a simplistic
“every line break is a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;“ rule wouldn’t work for Markdown.
Markdown’s email-style &lt;a href=&quot;#blockquote&quot;&gt;blockquoting&lt;/a&gt; and multi-paragraph &lt;a href=&quot;#list&quot;&gt;list items&lt;/a&gt;
work best – and look better – when you format them with hard breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Headers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports two styles of headers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://docutils.sourceforge.net/mirror/setext.html&quot;&gt;Setext&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aaronsw.com/2002/atx/&quot;&gt;atx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setext-style headers are “underlined” using equal signs (for first-level
headers) and dashes (for second-level headers). For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is an H1
=============

This is an H2
-------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any number of underlining &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;‘s or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;‘s will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atx-style headers use 1-6 hash characters at the start of the line,
corresponding to header levels 1-6. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# This is an H1

## This is an H2

###### This is an H6
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optionally, you may “close” atx-style headers. This is purely
cosmetic – you can use this if you think it looks better. The
closing hashes don’t even need to match the number of hashes
used to open the header. (The number of opening hashes
determines the header level.) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# This is an H1 #

## This is an H2 ##

### This is an H3 ######
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown uses email-style &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; characters for blockquoting. If you’re
familiar with quoting passages of text in an email message, then you
know how to create a blockquote in Markdown. It looks best if you hard
wrap the text and put a &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; before every line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; This is a blockquote with two paragraphs. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet,
&amp;gt; consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus.
&amp;gt; Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; Donec sit amet nisl. Aliquam semper ipsum sit amet velit. Suspendisse
&amp;gt; id sem consectetuer libero luctus adipiscing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown allows you to be lazy and only put the &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; before the first
line of a hard-wrapped paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; This is a blockquote with two paragraphs. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet,
consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus.
Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.

&amp;gt; Donec sit amet nisl. Aliquam semper ipsum sit amet velit. Suspendisse
id sem consectetuer libero luctus adipiscing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockquotes can be nested (i.e. a blockquote-in-a-blockquote) by
adding additional levels of &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; This is the first level of quoting.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; This is nested blockquote.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; Back to the first level.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockquotes can contain other Markdown elements, including headers, lists,
and code blocks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-a-header-&quot;&gt;This is a header.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the first list item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the second list item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s some example code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;return shell_exec(&amp;quot;echo $input | $markdown_script&amp;quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any decent text editor should make email-style quoting easy. For
example, with BBEdit, you can make a selection and choose Increase
Quote Level from the Text menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;list&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports ordered (numbered) and unordered (bulleted) lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unordered lists use asterisks, pluses, and hyphens – interchangably
– as list markers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   Red
*   Green
*   Blue
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;is equivalent to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+   Red
+   Green
+   Blue
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-   Red
-   Green
-   Blue
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ordered lists use numbers followed by periods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.  Bird
2.  McHale
3.  Parish
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the actual numbers you use to mark the
list have no effect on the HTML output Markdown produces. The HTML
Markdown produces from the above list is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Bird&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;McHale&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Parish&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you instead wrote the list in Markdown like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.  Bird
1.  McHale
1.  Parish
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;or even:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;3. Bird
1. McHale
8. Parish
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;you’d get the exact same HTML output. The point is, if you want to,
you can use ordinal numbers in your ordered Markdown lists, so that
the numbers in your source match the numbers in your published HTML.
But if you want to be lazy, you don’t have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do use lazy list numbering, however, you should still start the
list with the number 1. At some point in the future, Markdown may support
starting ordered lists at an arbitrary number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List markers typically start at the left margin, but may be indented by
up to three spaces. List markers must be followed by one or more spaces
or a tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make lists look nice, you can wrap items with hanging indents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.
    Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus. Vestibulum enim wisi,
    viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.
*   Donec sit amet nisl. Aliquam semper ipsum sit amet velit.
    Suspendisse id sem consectetuer libero luctus adipiscing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;But if you want to be lazy, you don’t have to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.
Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus. Vestibulum enim wisi,
viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.
*   Donec sit amet nisl. Aliquam semper ipsum sit amet velit.
Suspendisse id sem consectetuer libero luctus adipiscing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If list items are separated by blank lines, Markdown will wrap the
items in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags in the HTML output. For example, this input:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   Bird
*   Magic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will turn into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Bird&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Magic&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   Bird

*   Magic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will turn into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Bird&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Magic&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;List items may consist of multiple paragraphs. Each subsequent
paragraph in a list item must be indented by either 4 spaces
or one tab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.  This is a list item with two paragraphs. Lorem ipsum dolor
    sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit
    mi posuere lectus.

    Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet
    vitae, risus. Donec sit amet nisl. Aliquam semper ipsum
    sit amet velit.

2.  Suspendisse id sem consectetuer libero luctus adipiscing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It looks nice if you indent every line of the subsequent
paragraphs, but here again, Markdown will allow you to be
lazy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   This is a list item with two paragraphs.

    This is the second paragraph in the list item. You&amp;#39;re
only required to indent the first line. Lorem ipsum dolor
sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.

*   Another item in the same list.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put a blockquote within a list item, the blockquote’s &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
delimiters need to be indented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   A list item with a blockquote:

    &amp;gt; This is a blockquote
    &amp;gt; inside a list item.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put a code block within a list item, the code block needs
to be indented &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt; – 8 spaces or two tabs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   A list item with a code block:

        &amp;lt;code goes here&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that it’s possible to trigger an ordered list by
accident, by writing something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1986. What a great season.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, a &lt;em&gt;number-period-space&lt;/em&gt; sequence at the beginning of a
line. To avoid this, you can backslash-escape the period:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1986\. What a great season.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;precode&quot;&gt;Code Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-formatted code blocks are used for writing about programming or
markup source code. Rather than forming normal paragraphs, the lines
of a code block are interpreted literally. Markdown wraps a code block
in both &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To produce a code block in Markdown, simply indent every line of the
block by at least 4 spaces or 1 tab. For example, given this input:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is a normal paragraph:

    This is a code block.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown will generate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is a normal paragraph:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;This is a code block.
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;One level of indentation – 4 spaces or 1 tab – is removed from each
line of the code block. For example, this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Here is an example of AppleScript:

    tell application &amp;quot;Foo&amp;quot;
        beep
    end tell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will turn into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Here is an example of AppleScript:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;tell application &amp;quot;Foo&amp;quot;
    beep
end tell
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;A code block continues until it reaches a line that is not indented
(or the end of the article).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a code block, ampersands (&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;) and angle brackets (&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;)
are automatically converted into HTML entities. This makes it very
easy to include example HTML source code using Markdown – just paste
it and indent it, and Markdown will handle the hassle of encoding the
ampersands and angle brackets. For example, this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;footer&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;amp;copy; 2004 Foo Corporation
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will turn into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&amp;amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;footer&amp;quot;&amp;amp;gt;
    &amp;amp;amp;copy; 2004 Foo Corporation
&amp;amp;lt;/div&amp;amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular Markdown syntax is not processed within code blocks. E.g.,
asterisks are just literal asterisks within a code block. This means
it’s also easy to use Markdown to write about Markdown’s own syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hr&quot;&gt;Horizontal Rules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can produce a horizontal rule tag (&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;hr /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;) by placing three or
more hyphens, asterisks, or underscores on a line by themselves. If you
wish, you may use spaces between the hyphens or asterisks. Each of the
following lines will produce a horizontal rule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* * *

***

*****

- - -

---------------------------------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;span&quot;&gt;Span Elements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports two style of links: &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;reference&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both styles, the link text is delimited by [square brackets].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create an inline link, use a set of regular parentheses immediately
after the link text’s closing square bracket. Inside the parentheses,
put the URL where you want the link to point, along with an &lt;em&gt;optional&lt;/em&gt;
title for the link, surrounded in quotes. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is [an example](http://example.com/ &amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;) inline link.

[This link](http://example.net/) has no title attribute.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will produce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://example.com/&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
an example&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; inline link.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://example.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;This link&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; has no
title attribute.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re referring to a local resource on the same server, you can
use relative paths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;See my [About](/about/) page for details.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reference-style links use a second set of square brackets, inside
which you place a label of your choosing to identify the link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is [an example][id] reference-style link.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can optionally use a space to separate the sets of brackets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is [an example] [id] reference-style link.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, anywhere in the document, you define your link label like this,
on a line by itself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[id]: http://example.com/  &amp;quot;Optional Title Here&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Square brackets containing the link identifier (optionally
indented from the left margin using up to three spaces);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;followed by a colon;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;followed by one or more spaces (or tabs);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;followed by the URL for the link;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optionally followed by a title attribute for the link, enclosed
in double or single quotes, or enclosed in parentheses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following three link definitions are equivalent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com/&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title Here&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com/&quot;&gt;http://example.com/&lt;/a&gt;  ‘Optional Title Here’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; There is a known bug in Markdown.pl 1.0.1 which prevents
single quotes from being used to delimit link titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link URL may, optionally, be surrounded by angle brackets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[id]: &amp;lt;http://example.com/&amp;gt;  &amp;quot;Optional Title Here&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can put the title attribute on the next line and use extra spaces
or tabs for padding, which tends to look better with longer URLs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[id]: http://example.com/longish/path/to/resource/here
    &amp;quot;Optional Title Here&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Link definitions are only used for creating links during Markdown
processing, and are stripped from your document in the HTML output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link definition names may consist of letters, numbers, spaces, and
punctuation – but they are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; case sensitive. E.g. these two
links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  [link text][a]
  [link text][A]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;are equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;implicit link name&lt;/em&gt; shortcut allows you to omit the name of the
link, in which case the link text itself is used as the name.
Just use an empty set of square brackets – e.g., to link the word
“Google” to the google.com web site, you could simply write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then define the link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because link names may contain spaces, this shortcut even works for
multiple words in the link text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then define the link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link definitions can be placed anywhere in your Markdown document. I
tend to put them immediately after each paragraph in which they’re
used, but if you want, you can put them all at the end of your
document, sort of like footnotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of reference links in action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I get 10 times more traffic from [Google] [1] than from
[Yahoo] [2] or [MSN] [3].

  [1]: http://google.com/        &amp;quot;Google&amp;quot;
  [2]: http://search.yahoo.com/  &amp;quot;Yahoo Search&amp;quot;
  [3]: http://search.msn.com/    &amp;quot;MSN Search&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the implicit link name shortcut, you could instead write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I get 10 times more traffic from [Google][] than from
[Yahoo][] or [MSN][].

  [google]: http://google.com/        &amp;quot;Google&amp;quot;
  [yahoo]:  http://search.yahoo.com/  &amp;quot;Yahoo Search&amp;quot;
  [msn]:    http://search.msn.com/    &amp;quot;MSN Search&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both of the above examples will produce the following HTML output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I get 10 times more traffic from &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://google.com/&amp;quot;
title=&amp;quot;Google&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; than from
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://search.yahoo.com/&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Yahoo Search&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Yahoo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
or &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://search.msn.com/&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;MSN Search&amp;quot;&amp;gt;MSN&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;For comparison, here is the same paragraph written using
Markdown’s inline link style:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I get 10 times more traffic from [Google](http://google.com/ &amp;quot;Google&amp;quot;)
than from [Yahoo](http://search.yahoo.com/ &amp;quot;Yahoo Search&amp;quot;) or
[MSN](http://search.msn.com/ &amp;quot;MSN Search&amp;quot;).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The point of reference-style links is not that they’re easier to
write. The point is that with reference-style links, your document
source is vastly more readable. Compare the above examples: using
reference-style links, the paragraph itself is only 81 characters
long; with inline-style links, it’s 176 characters; and as raw HTML,
it’s 234 characters. In the raw HTML, there’s more markup than there
is text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Markdown’s reference-style links, a source document much more
closely resembles the final output, as rendered in a browser. By
allowing you to move the markup-related metadata out of the paragraph,
you can add links without interrupting the narrative flow of your
prose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;em&quot;&gt;Emphasis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown treats asterisks (&lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt;) and underscores (&lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt;) as indicators of
emphasis. Text wrapped with one &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; will be wrapped with an
HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag; double &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt;‘s or &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt;‘s will be wrapped with an HTML
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag. E.g., this input:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*single asterisks*

_single underscores_

**double asterisks**

__double underscores__
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will produce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;single asterisks&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;single underscores&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;double asterisks&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;double underscores&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use whichever style you prefer; the lone restriction is that
the same character must be used to open and close an emphasis span.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emphasis can be used in the middle of a word:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;un*frigging*believable
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;But if you surround an &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; with spaces, it’ll be treated as a
literal asterisk or underscore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To produce a literal asterisk or underscore at a position where it
would otherwise be used as an emphasis delimiter, you can backslash
escape it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\*this text is surrounded by literal asterisks\*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To indicate a span of code, wrap it with backtick quotes (&lt;code&gt;` &lt;/code&gt;).
Unlike a pre-formatted code block, a code span indicates code within a
normal paragraph. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Use the `printf()` function.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will produce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Use the &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;printf()&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; function.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;To include a literal backtick character within a code span, you can use
multiple backticks as the opening and closing delimiters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;``There is a literal backtick (`) here.``
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;which will produce this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;There is a literal backtick (`) here.&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The backtick delimiters surrounding a code span may include spaces –
one after the opening, one before the closing. This allows you to place
literal backtick characters at the beginning or end of a code span:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  A single backtick in a code span: &lt;code&gt;` &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  A backtick-delimited string in a code span: &lt;code&gt;`foo` &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will produce:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A single backtick in a code span: &lt;code&gt;`&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A backtick-delimited string in a code span: &lt;code&gt;&lt;code&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a code span, ampersands and angle brackets are encoded as HTML
entities automatically, which makes it easy to include example HTML
tags. Markdown will turn this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Please don&amp;#39;t use any `&amp;lt;blink&amp;gt;` tags.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please don&amp;#39;t use any &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&amp;amp;lt;blink&amp;amp;gt;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; tags.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can write this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;`&amp;amp;#8212;` is the decimal-encoded equivalent of `&amp;amp;mdash;`.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;to produce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;#8212;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; is the decimal-encoded
equivalent of &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;mdash;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;img&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, it’s fairly difficult to devise a “natural” syntax for
placing images into a plain text document format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown uses an image syntax that is intended to resemble the syntax
for links, allowing for two styles: &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;reference&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline image syntax looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Alt text](/path/to/img.jpg)

![Alt text](/path/to/img.jpg &amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exclamation mark: &lt;code&gt;!&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;followed by a set of square brackets, containing the &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt;
attribute text for the image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;followed by a set of parentheses, containing the URL or path to
the image, and an optional &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; attribute enclosed in double
or single quotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference-style image syntax looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Alt text][id]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where “id” is the name of a defined image reference. Image references
are defined using syntax identical to link references:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[id]: url/to/image  &amp;quot;Optional title attribute&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, Markdown has no syntax for specifying the
dimensions of an image; if this is important to you, you can simply
use regular HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;misc&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;autolink&quot;&gt;Automatic Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports a shortcut style for creating “automatic” links for URLs and email addresses: simply surround the URL or email address with angle brackets. What this means is that if you want to show the actual text of a URL or email address, and also have it be a clickable link, you can do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;http://example.com/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown will turn this into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://example.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://example.com/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automatic links for email addresses work similarly, except that
Markdown will also perform a bit of randomized decimal and hex
entity-encoding to help obscure your address from address-harvesting
spambots. For example, Markdown will turn this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;address@example.com&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;into something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;&amp;amp;#x6D;&amp;amp;#x61;i&amp;amp;#x6C;&amp;amp;#x74;&amp;amp;#x6F;:&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x65;
&amp;amp;#115;&amp;amp;#115;&amp;amp;#64;&amp;amp;#101;&amp;amp;#120;&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#109;&amp;amp;#x70;&amp;amp;#x6C;e&amp;amp;#x2E;&amp;amp;#99;&amp;amp;#111;
&amp;amp;#109;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x65;&amp;amp;#115;&amp;amp;#115;&amp;amp;#64;&amp;amp;#101;&amp;amp;#120;&amp;amp;#x61;
&amp;amp;#109;&amp;amp;#x70;&amp;amp;#x6C;e&amp;amp;#x2E;&amp;amp;#99;&amp;amp;#111;&amp;amp;#109;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;which will render in a browser as a clickable link to “address@example.com”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This sort of entity-encoding trick will indeed fool many, if not
most, address-harvesting bots, but it definitely won’t fool all of
them. It’s better than nothing, but an address published in this way
will probably eventually start receiving spam.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;backslash&quot;&gt;Backslash Escapes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown allows you to use backslash escapes to generate literal
characters which would otherwise have special meaning in Markdown’s
formatting syntax. For example, if you wanted to surround a word
with literal asterisks (instead of an HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag), you can use
backslashes before the asterisks, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\*literal asterisks\*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown provides backslash escapes for the following characters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\   backslash
`   backtick
*   asterisk
_   underscore
{}  curly braces
[]  square brackets
()  parentheses
#   hash mark
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plus sign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minus sign (hyphen)
.   dot
!   exclamation mark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>